Look, look!
快来看 快来看
There's a dinosaur.
有恐龙呢
Fine!
真是的
Just in a blink of an eye and he's gone.
一转眼就不见人影了
Take it, you must be thirsty.
来 你一定渴了吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Oh no! Only three minutes left!
糟糕 只剩三分钟了
What's wrong, Shinichi?
怎么了 新一
Great! We made it.
太好了 总算赶上了
Where is this? Just an ordinary square.
这是哪里 只是个普通的广场嘛
Just wait and see.
你等着看就知道了
What?
怎么了
The fountain here sprays every two hours.
这里每隔两小时就会喷一次水
I remember you love this feeling the most, right?
你应该最喜欢这种感觉的吧
Shinichi.
新一
This is my gift to you to celebrate your victory in the karate competition.
这就作为庆祝你在空手道大赛得到优胜的礼物吧
You must cherish this gift.
你可要心怀感激地收下喔
Come on, this is no big deal, all right?
少来了 好像有多了不起似的
It's a rainbow.
是彩虹啊
Great, let's drink to that.
好 我们来干杯吧
Okay.
好
You look so funny.
你的样子真好笑
(Detective Conan   Captured in Her Eyes)
「瞳孔中的暗杀者」
I am high school detective, Shinichi Kudo.
我是高中生侦探 工藤新一
When I went to the amusement park with my childhood friend, Ran Mouri,
在一次与青梅竹马的小兰到游乐园时
I witnessed a suspicious transaction made by a man in black.
现场目击了黑衣男子进行可疑交易
I was too preoccupied with watching at that time,
专注于偷看交易进行的我
and didn't notice another accomplice approaching from behind.
没有察觉到从身后接近的另一名黑衣男子
He made me take the poison by force.
我被那个男人灌下毒药
When I woke up,
当我醒来时…
my body became smaller.
身体竟然缩小了
If those guys knew that Shinichi Kudo was still alive,
如果让那些家伙知道工藤新一还活着
not only would my life be in danger,
不但小命不保 还会危及到身边亲友的安全
At the suggestion of Professor Agasa, I concealed my true identity.
在阿笠博士的建议下我隐藏了真实身份
When Ran asked for my name,
在小兰问我名字的时候
I came up with the name of Conan Edogawa.
灵机一动回答说自己叫江户川柯南
In order to collect information about those guys,
为了得到那些黑衣人的情报
I moved in with Ran whose father is a detective.
就寄住在了父亲是侦探的小兰家
Detective Mouri!
毛利名侦探
Please talk about the logic of your deduction this time.
请谈谈这次的推理重点
Actually, I don't remember much.
其实我已经记不清楚了
Of course he doesn't remember. Because every time,
那还用说 因为我每次
I would use Stun-Gun Wristwatch to make him unconscious,
都会用手表型麻醉枪使他昏迷
and then use Voice-Changing Bowtie
再用蝴蝶结变声器
to solve the case with Uncle Mouri's voice.
以叔叔的声音来破案
Both are invented by Professor Agasa.
这两样都是阿笠博士的发明
Nice to meet you.
请多指教
In addition, the Professor also invented
此外 博士还发明了
Turbo Engine Skateboard,
配备涡轮引擎的滑板
Criminal Tracking Glasses,
犯人追踪眼镜
Power-Enhancing Kick Shoes
增强功率的运动鞋
and all kinds of unique gadgets.
以及各种独一无二的发明
Neither Ran nor Uncle Mouri realized my true identity.
小兰和叔叔都未发现我的真实身份
The only ones who know about this are Professor Agasa,
知道此事的 只有阿笠博士
Heiji Hattori, a high school detective from Kansai,
关西的高中生侦探 服部平次
and Ai Haibara, my classmate.
还有我的同学 灰原哀
She used to work with those men in black.
她原本和那些黑衣人是同伙
When she escaped from the organization,
在逃出该组织之际
she took the same drug as me.
也服下了和我同样的药物
After that, her body has also become smaller.
从此身体就缩小了
Black Organization remains a mystery,
黑衣组织目前仍是个谜
but now between Ran and me,
而现在的我和小兰之间
there is a thick and tall barrier.
却隔了一道厚重高大的屏障
Although my body is smaller, my mind is still flexible.
身体虽然变小了但头脑依旧灵活
I am the famous omniscient detective.
无所不知的名侦探
Only one truth will prevail!
真相永远只有一个
Fountain?
喷水池
Yeah. The rainbow emerged afterwards was really beautiful, right?
是啊 后来出现的彩虹好美啊
Yeah, right.
没错
Come on, why does she always remember those boring things?
拜托 怎么老是记着些无聊的事
Let's go back to Tropical Land later.
我们以后再去热带乐园吧
We haven't been there since that day.
我们从那天起就再也没去过了
That's because I've become smaller since that day.
因为从那天起我就变小了嘛
When should we go?
我们什么时候去好呢
Well...
这个嘛
I don't know if Conan-kun is home.
不知道柯南在不在家
Yes, I don't know either.
是呀 不知道在不在
It would be bad if he's not home.
要是不在就糟了
Sorry, Ran.
不好意思 小兰
I have a case to handle.
我还有案子要处理
I'll call you later. Bye.
我以后再打电话给你 再见
Wait a minute, Shinichi.
等一下 新一
Fine!
真是的
Case, case, case...
案子 案子 案子
A jerk who only cares about cases!
只知道办案子的混蛋
Conan-kun definitely can't guess the right answer this time!
柯南这次一定不知道答案
I wish I could have seen him admit defeat earlier.
真想早点看到他认输的表情呢
Conan-kun admitted defeat.
柯南认输了
I admit defeat. I am a loser.
我认输了 甘拜下风
What are you three smirking at?
你们三个在傻笑什么啊
Conan-kun.
柯南
You're just in time.
你来得正好
We were just about to go find you.
我们正打算去你家
We came up with an ultimate IQ quiz!
我们想到一个终极智力题
IQ quiz?
智力题
Listen carefully.
你听好了
When we asked Haibara-san
我们问灰原同学
what kind of person she thought Conan-kun was,
认为柯南是个怎样的人时
she looked at the moon and said, "I can't say he's summer."
她就看着月亮说 不是夏天吧
Haibara-san was: one, complimenting you;
灰原是在 一 夸奖你
two, belittling you.
二 贬低你
Which is the answer?
答案是哪个呢
She couldn't say I was summer.
她说我不是夏天
Moon... I see.
月亮 我知道了
The answer is two.
答案是二
Why?
为什么
The summer moon appears in June, July and August.
夏天的月亮出现在6 7 8月
It means "not a normal human being".
意思是说 「不是常人」
Awesome. Conan knows everything.
好厉害 柯南果然名不虚传
It's not funny at all.
真没意思
By the way, what were you smirking at?
对了 你们刚才笑什么
Then, are you willing to admit defeat?
那你愿意认输吗
Cross the road!
快过马路
Wait! You can't cross!
慢着 不能过去
The flashing green light indicates the same meaning as the yellow light.
闪绿灯和亮黄灯代表相同意思
You should wait for the next green light to cross.
请你们等下一个绿灯再过吧
Yes, sir.
是
We were lectured all of a sudden.
平白无故被骂了一顿
Anyway, that man was right.
没办法 那个叔叔说的没错
This time it's my turn to ask the question.
这次轮到我出题了
What is his profession?
那个叔叔的职业是什么
Is he a school teacher?
是学校的老师吗
He doesn't look like a salesman either. He doesn't have a briefcase.
也不像业务员 他没带着皮包
Is he an Unadon vendor?
是不是卖鳗鱼饭的
The answer is a police officer.
答案是刑警
A police officer?
刑警
When taking notes,
刑警在作笔记时
police officers always open the police manuals in landscape orientation,
都会将警察手册横着打开
and then make notes in landscape orientation.
再横向作记录
So that's it.
原来如此
Conan is amazing.
柯南真厉害
You really know everything.
你什么都知道
The light has turned green. Let's go.
变绿灯了 我们过去吧
Okay!
好
The police officer was shot!
那个叔叔中弹了
That person is the murderer!
那人是凶手
I won't let you escape!
休想逃走
Conan-kun, watch out!
柯南 危险
Call an ambulance!
快去叫救护车
I see!
知道了
Damn, he got away!
可恶 被他逃掉了
Officer, hang in there!
叔叔 振作点
Who shot at you?
是谁向你开枪的
What?
什么
At around 2:00 p.m. today,
今天下午两点左右
current police officer Osamu Narasawa was shot dead
在米花公园的红绿灯旁
near a traffic light in Beika Park.
现任刑警奈良泽治遭到枪杀
The killer is still at large.
凶手目前仍在逃逸中
The Metropolitan Police Department has sent extra police support
警视厅已加派警力支援
and has set up the research headquarters at Beika Police Station.
并将搜查总部设在米花警局
I'm sorry, but I must ask you some questions again.
抱歉 要再重复问你们些问题
What are the characteristics of the killer?
凶手有何特征
He's a young man.
是个年轻男人
No, she's a beautiful young woman.
不对 是个漂亮的大姐姐
You're wrong. He's a middle-aged man.
错了 是个中年叔叔
And what color was the umbrella he was holding?
那他撑的伞是什么颜色
It was a black umbrella.
是把黑伞
It was a green one! Green!
是绿伞 绿的
I remember it was blue.
我记得是蓝色的
Did you really see the killer?
你们真的看到了吗
Conan-kun, can you tell me?
柯南你说说
Both his raincoat and umbrella are gray.
雨衣和伞是灰色的
I don't know if the killer is a man or a woman.
是男是女就不知道了
But that person was holding the umbrella with the right hand.
不过他是用右手撑伞的
So, he used his left hand to shoot.
这么说来 他是用左手开的枪
The murderer is left-handed.
凶手是个左撇子
Inspector Megure, if you don't mind,
目暮警官 请问
why did Officer Narasawa clutch his left chest when he died?
奈良泽警官断气时抓着左胸代表什么意思
He was trying to suggest the police manual on his chest.
他是想暗示胸口的警察手册
We've found that out.
这点我们已经查清
We are currently working on
目前我们正就手册中的内容
investigating the contents of the manual.
进行彻底的调查
Inspector Megure.
目暮警官
Judging from the bullet casings left at the scene,
根据现场掉落的弹壳发现
the pistol used by the killer
凶手使用的手枪为
is a 9 mm automatic pistol.
9毫米口径的自动手枪
9 mm caliber...
9毫米口径
That kind of pistol is generally used by women.
那是女人惯用的手枪
Luckily, all of you were not involved.
不过还好你们都没受到波及
Conan-kun, you too.
柯南你也是
Damn, if the light hadn't changed to red,
可恶 如果当时没变红灯的话
I wouldn't have lost him.
我就不会跟丢了
(The Current Police Officer Got Killed in His Own Basement)
(现任刑警死于自家地下室)
(Was It the Work of a Radical?)
(是激进人士所为吗)
(The Police Force is Facing a Challenge)
(警界面临挑战)
It's Megure.
我是目暮
Oh, it's you, Mouri.
是毛利老弟啊
Inspector Megure.
目暮警官
I want to ask you more about last night's case.
关于昨晚的案子 我想询问一下详细情况
Sorry, I'm being busy.
抱歉 我正在忙
I'll call you later.
稍后再联络
Hello, hello! Inspector Megure?
喂喂 目暮警官
What's wrong?
怎么了
He said he was busy.
他说他正忙着
Of course.
那当然了
There are already two police officers who died.
都已经死了两名刑警了
He's really different from his usual self.
和平时的目暮警官还真是判若两人呢
Listen up, Shiratori.
你听好 白鸟老弟
This case is a secret within the police department.
这件案子是警局内部的秘密
You must not mention it to anyone.
绝对不能对外人提起
I understand.
我明白
Two current police officers were shot dead.
两名现任刑警遭到枪杀
The bullet casings left at the scene are exactly the same.
歹徒使用的子弹弹壳一致
The police have confirmed that both were killed by the same murderer.
警方已确认凶手是同一人
The relevant clues are still under investigation.
相关线索目前正在调查中
Next is the weather report.
接下来是天气预报
(Beika Sun Plaza Hotel)
「米花太阳广场饭店」
What the hell?
怎么搞的
Officer Shiratori's sister really chose a good timing.
白鸟警官的妹妹可真会挑时间
How come she's gonna hold the wedding party at this time like this?
偏偏在这时候举行婚宴
I guess she has no choice.
那也是没办法的事
The date was set a month ago.
日期是一个月前定下来的
Anyway, we can't blame her for this.
再说发生这种事也不能怪她
Besides, it's not some kind of wedding party.
而且这也不是什么婚宴
It's just a wedding celebration.
只是结婚庆祝会
The organizer is a friend of the bride and groom.
主办人是新郎新娘的朋友
I got it, all right?
我知道了啦
What do you think the groom, Haretsuki, will be like?
你们说 新郎晴月会是个怎样的人
I heard he's a painter.
听说是个画家
A little-known painter, to be exact.
还只是个名不见经传的画家
A little-known painter?
名不见经传的画家
If so, then I'll give up making friends with him.
那我就不考虑和他交朋友了
Your handwriting is as ugly as before.
你写的字还是那么丑
Mom!
妈妈
They also invited you?
他们也邀请你了吗
Yes, Sara's a legal intern now.
没错 沙罗现在是准律师
Naturally, we know each other.
我们自然认识
Auntie, your handwriting is so beautiful.
阿姨你的字可真漂亮
Funny. You're a couple. Why are you signing separately?
真是的 夫妻俩干嘛分开签名
Sorry to trouble you.
麻烦你了
I'll put your bag in locker 87.
您的皮包放在87号柜
We're going, Conan-kun.
走吧 柯南
Wow, there are so many people here.
啊呀 来的人可真多
Inspector Megure is here too.
目暮警官也来了
You can tell a policeman at a glance.
做警察的一眼就可以看出来了
Their eyes are always sharp.
个个眼神犀利
They always have serious expressions.
气氛凝重
It's hardly surprising.
这也难怪
Because of that case,
为了调查那件案子
it's impossible for them to think of anything else.
他们根本无心玩乐
But Officer Sato is always cheerful.
倒是佐藤警官一直挺开朗的
What do you think? Clothes make the man, right?
如何 佛要金装人要衣装对吧
No such thing.
没那回事
You're already pretty.
你本来就很漂亮
It's Director Odagiri. I gotta go and say hello to him.
是小田切局长 我去打声招呼
Who is he?
他是谁
Director Odagiri.
小田切局长
When your father was a young and inexperienced detective,
你爸这个烂侦探在当警察时 他还只是个课长
Now he's already the Director-general of the Criminal Affairs Bureau.
现在已经是刑事局局长了
Distinguished guests, sorry to keep you waiting.
各位来宾久等了
Now we have the bride and groom coming out.
现在欢迎新郎新娘出场
Please give a warm applause to welcome them.
请大家以热烈的掌声欢迎
So beautiful!
好漂亮啊
Kotaro, Sara, congratulations!
光太郎 沙罗 恭喜你们
Mouri-san.
毛利先生
Congratulations!
恭喜恭喜
Thank you.
谢谢
Let me introduce you.
我来介绍一下
This is my attending physician.
这位是我的主治医师
Dr. Kazato from department of cardiology of Beika Yakushi Hospital.
米花药师野医院 心疗科的风户医生
My family name is Kazato. Nice to see you.
敝姓风户 请多指教
Mine is Mouri.
敝姓毛利
This is my wife Eri and my daughter Ran.
这是内人英理和小女小兰
This is Conan. He temporarily lives in my house.
他是寄住我家的柯南
Is it necessary to say "temporarily lives"?
「寄住」这两字就不用说了吧
So, Officer Shiratori, you are seeing a psychiatrist?
白鸟警官 你在看心理医生
Well, actually, there are a lot of annoying things at work.
不 其实在工作上常会碰到许多恼人的事情
I have no other choice.
我也是出于无奈
Mouri-san, I think you'd better come to see a psychiatrist too.
毛利先生 你最好也来看看
Indeed. These days my memory...
说得也是 最近我的记忆…
Nonsense! What do you mean?
可恶 你什么意思啊
You're in no position to laugh at me, all right?
还轮不到你来笑我
It hurts!
好痛
Would you excuse me for just a minute?
我失陪一下
Inspector Megure!
目暮警官
Oh, Mouri-kun.
是你啊 毛利老弟
How's the follow-up investigation going?
后续调查情况如何
Sorry, I don't want to talk about it.
抱歉 我不想谈此事
Why doesn't he talk to me?
为何不肯跟我谈
There must be something he can't tell you.
一定有什么事不能告诉叔叔你吧
Is that so, Takagi?
是这样吗 高木
No such thing.
没有啊
Officer Takagi, you like Officer Sato, don't you?
高木警官 你喜欢佐藤警官对吧
That's interesting.
有意思
Then, let me be your messenger of love.
我就把你的心事告诉她吧
Wait, I'll tell you.
等一下 我说就是了
But you gotta promise me you won't tell reporters.
不过千万别让媒体知道
In fact, Officer Shiba died holding a police manual.
芝警官是握着警察手册而死的
What?
什么
If so...
这么说
Mouri-san, you don't need to ask any further questions.
毛利先生 你就不用往下问了
Need not to know.
Need not to know
Now you understand, don't you?
这下你该清楚了吧
"Need not to know"?
Need not to know 「无须知道」
Does that mean I don't need to know about this thing?
是说我无须知道此事吗
How can that be?
竟有这种事
Need not to know.
Need not to know
This is a common jargon among police officers.
这是刑警间惯用的隐语
Is it possible that the murderer
难道这个凶手
is related to the police force?
是警界相关人士吗
And the relationship is unusual.
而且关系还不寻常
Maybe he's some top person at the police force.
也许是警方上级人员
Or even he can influence the entire police organization.
甚至关系到整个警察组织
He never proposed to you or did something like that?
他没对你说求婚之类的话
Yeah, he's not good at saying that kind of thing.
是啊 他是最不会说这些的
For me, this kind of man is better.
这种男人反而好
I don't like those honey-lipped guys. They're all cunning.
伶牙俐齿的家伙都不是什么好货
Mom, I've been meaning to ask you.
妈妈 以前我就一直想问你
How did Dad propose to you?
爸爸是怎么向你求婚的
By speaking those nasty words, of course.
还不就是那些肉麻兮兮的话
Sensei, tell us about it.
老师 说来听听嘛
But I've forgotten all.
可是我都忘了
Come on, drop the act.
少来了 您别装蒜了
I can use it as a reference for the future.
我可以当成以后的参考啊
Mom, don't be so secretive.
妈妈 你就别再卖关子了
I think he was saying, I love you so, so much.
他好像是说 我真的好爱你
I love you more than any other person on this planet.
比这地球上的任何一个人都要爱
No way...
不会吧
How romantic!
真浪漫
If Shinichi had said the same things to me...
要是新一跟我这么说的话…
I can tell what you're thinking at a glance.
一看就知道你在想什么
I'm not!
我哪有
What's wrong, Ran-nee-chan?
你怎么了 小兰姐姐
Your face is so red.
你的脸好红啊
It's nothing.
没什么啦
Toshiya, this is not a place for you.
敏也 这里不是你该来的地方
I don't think you've been invited to this party.
你应该没被邀请来参加这个派对吧
Stop nagging!
吵死人了
I came to this hotel only because of work.
我是因为工作才会到这家酒店的
That's his son, Toshiya-san.
那个人是他的儿子敏也
I heard he's in a rock band.
听说在搞摇滚乐团
Don't be angry, Director.
你就别生气了 局长
Toshiya-kun, you can stay...
敏也 你就留下来…
Get out!
出去
Don't come here looking for food, you wild dog.
你这野狗少来这里找食吃
What did you say?
你说什么
Toshiya-san.
敏也
Sorry to have disturbed you all.
抱歉打搅了
I think I've seen that woman somewhere.
我好像在哪儿看过那女的
Sato-kun.
佐藤
About that thing...
关于那件事
I'm fine.
我没事
But...
可是
Don't worry about me.
您就别担心了
Locker 38, please.
38号柜 谢谢
Okay.
好的
Ran-chan, it's you.
是小兰啊
Officer Sato.
佐藤警官
It's a weird party with all the cops here, isn't it?
这里全是警察 聚会的气氛很怪吧
It's okay, but then again...
还好啦 不过话说回来
Officer Sato, you should be careful.
佐藤警官你自己也要小心啊
What do you mean?
怎么说
There are so many police officers killed one after another these days.
最近刑警陆续遇害
Don't worry, It's not that easy to kill me.
放心 我是很强悍的
What's wrong?
怎么了
The power is out.
停电了
What happened?
出了什么事
It's really strange.
真奇怪
I'll go check it out. You stay here.
我去看看情况 你别乱动
Officer Sato, there's a flashlight here.
佐藤警官 这里有手电筒
What?
什么
Look.
你看
Ran-san, put it down!
小兰 快放下
Officer Sato!
佐藤警官
Officer Sato, hang in there!
佐藤警官 你振作点
It's my fault.
都怪我
It's all my fault for taking the flashlight.
都怪我拿了手电筒
Ran!
小兰
Officer Sato!
佐藤警官
Ran, are you all right?
小兰 你没事吧
Ran-nee-chan just passed out.
小兰姐只是昏过去而已
The one who is seriously injured was...
受重伤的是…
Officer Sato!
佐藤警官
Officer Sato, hang in there!
佐藤警官 你振作点
This is...
这是
Megure, call an ambulance!
目暮 快叫救护车
Shiratori, block all the entrances and exits of the hotel.
白鸟 封锁饭店所有出入口
Yes, sir.
是
Hello? This is the 15th floor of the Beika Sun Plaza Hotel.
喂喂 这里是米花太阳广场饭店15楼
A woman was shot.
有名女性遭到枪击
Please send an ambulance immediately.
请立刻派辆救护车过来
The magazine is empty.
弹匣都空了
9 mm automatic pistol.
9毫米口径的自动手枪
The murderer is the same person.
凶手是同一个人
But, why is there a flashlight here?
不过 这里怎么会有手电筒
Hurry up!
动作快点
Block all entrances and exits!
封锁所有出入口
Everyone except children must be identified for gunshot residues.
除了儿童以外所有人都要测试硝烟反应
No one is exempt.
没有人可以例外
Including me and all the police officers.
包括我和所有刑警都要测试
Of course, this bastard is included too.
当然也包括这个混蛋
Why is he still here?
这个人还在这里啊
But those two person are gone.
不过那两人却不见了
Inspector Megure, how is Officer Sato?
目暮警官 佐藤警官怎么样
A bullet struck close to her heart.
一颗子弹停在心脏附近
She only have a 50% chance of survival.
想要救活 只有五成可能
Inspector Megure, how about Ran?
目暮警官 小兰呢
Luckily, she's not injured, but she's not awake yet.
幸好没受外伤 但她还未清醒
Her ward is over there.
她的病房就在里面
Ran should be fine.
小兰应该没事
But the strangest part is the flashlight.
我想不通的是那支手电筒
Could it be that...
难道说
How's the investigation going, Shiratori-kun?
白鸟老弟 调查进行得如何
We've identified all the people for gunshot residues.
已对所有的人进行了硝烟测试
But there is no reaction.
但是全无反应
No reaction?
全无反应
I'm afraid the murderer had run away before we blocked entrances and exits.
凶手恐怕在封锁前就逃走了
Is there any fingerprint on the pistol?
手枪上有采集到指纹吗
No fingerprints either.
也没有指纹
Chiba-kun, the switchboard was rigged, right?
千叶 配电盘被动过手脚吧
Yes, it was.
是的
It's probably a device that can be detonated by cell phone.
应该是通过移动电话进行引爆的一种装置
I have been feeling like something's wrong.
我一直觉得有点不对劲
Did Officer Sato
厕所里的那支手电筒
hold the flashlight in the toilet from the beginning?
是否一开始就握在佐藤警官的手上
I don't think so.
我想应该不是
The locker under the toilet table was open, right?
梳妆台下的置物柜是开着的吧
Maybe the flashlight was originally put there.
可能手电筒原本是放在那里的
And the light was on.
而且一直就开着
What? So the murderer...
什么 那么凶手…
I see.
原来如此
No one would have noticed when the light was on.
灯开着的时候谁都不会注意到
Looks like this incident is related to that case.
看来此事与那个案子应该也脱不了关系
What case?
什么案子
Well...
这个…
Why don't you just tell me?
为什么不说出来呢
Ran was almost shot, wasn't she?
小兰差一点就中弹了啊
Inspector Megure!
目暮警官
Something went wrong! Ran...
不好了 小兰她…
What's wrong with Ran?
小兰怎么了
Although she's awake, she looks kind of weird.
虽然清醒了 但样子有点不太对劲
What?
什么
Ran-nee-chan!
小兰姐
Are you okay, Ran-nee-chan?
你还好吧 小兰姐
Who are you, kid?
小弟弟 你是谁
Not only does she not remember us,
她不仅不记得我们
she can't even remember her own name.
就连她自己的名字也想不起来了
Impossible.
不可能
I'm your father, Kogoro Mouri.
我是你爸爸毛利小五郎
She's your mother, Eri Kisaki.
她是你妈妈妃英理
I don't remember. I can't remember anything.
我不记得了 什么都想不起来了
Ran.
兰
Dr. Kazato.
风户医生
I'm sorry to call you over here at this hour.
您累了一天了还找您过来 真是抱歉
The doctor on duty at the department of cardiology is not here.
因为心疗科的值班大夫不在
Do you know who you are?
你知道自己是谁吗
Do you remember what happened today?
那记得今天发生了什么事吗
No.
不记得
Where is the capital of the United States?
美国的首都在哪里
Washington, D.C.
华盛顿
What is 5 times 8?
5乘8等于多少
Please press out the refill of this ballpoint pen.
请将这支原子笔的笔芯按出来
Retrograde amnesia?
逆向健忘
Yes.
对
This is a memory disorder caused by sudden illness or trauma
这是因突发的疾病或外伤
that results in the loss of access to events and information of the past.
造成失去事发前记忆的一种记忆障碍
But in the case of your daughter,
不过就令嫒的状况来看
I'm afraid it's due to the psychological shock
恐怕是亲眼看到佐藤警官中枪
after seeing Officer Sato getting shot.
精神上受到过大冲击所致
Then, will my daughter's memory come back?
那小女的记忆能恢复吗
I can't say for sure at this point.
就目前的状况来看我也很难下定论
But I think this won't affect her daily life.
但日常的生活起居应该都没有什么大碍
Are you saying that she can still live her life as usual?
这么说 她仍然能照常生活对吧
Yes.
没错
But, anyway, I think it's better to stay in the hospital for a few days for observation.
不过我看最好还是暂时住院观察几天比较好
Indeed, it's natural that Ran would be shocked
亲眼看到认识的刑警遭到枪击
after seeing an officer she knows getting shot.
小兰会受刺激是理所当然的
But there should be another reason
但会造成记忆丧失
for the memory loss.
难道其中另有原因
There must be something that made Ran heartbroken.
一定有什么事刺伤了小兰的心
Officer Sato's operation has been done.
佐藤警官动完手术了
Finally, that bullet has been removed.
子弹总算是取出来了
As for whether she can survive, it depends on luck.
但能不能得救就要看天意了
Is that so?
是吗
Inspector Megure!
目暮警官
Things have become this terrible. Why can't you just tell me?
事到如今 你还不能开诚布公吗
Shiratori, you must know. Tell me!
白鸟 你一定知道 告诉我
I promise we will bring the murderer to justice.
我们一定会将凶手绳之以法
Damn it!
可恶
Officer Chiba.
千叶警官
Did you check the fingerprints on the flashlight in the toilet?
是否调查过掉在厕所里的手电筒上的指纹
Yes.
查过了
But we only found Ran-san's fingerprints.
但只找到小兰的指纹
We thought it was Officer Sato who held the flashlight.
我们本以为拿手电筒的是佐藤警官
But it was Ran-san, in fact.
其实却是小兰
If that's true, Ran must think that she was responsible for Officer Sato's incident.
如果真是如此 小兰一定认为佐藤警官中枪是她所害
So Ran-kun was stimulated and lost her memory because of this.
这么说小兰就是受到这个刺激才会丧失记忆的
Ran.
兰
Even if you can't regain your memory for the rest of your life,
就算你一辈子都无法恢复记忆
I will always
我也永远
be your friend.
是你的朋友
I'll speak out everything.
我就将一切都说出来吧
But Inspector Megure, it's inappropriate, isn't it?
可是目暮警官 这不妥吧
What's the big deal?
怕什么
If I'm fired, I'll open a detective agency just like Mouri-kun.
真被革职的话 我就学毛利老弟开家侦探事务所
Inspector Megure...
目暮警官
Takagi-kun, you're in charge of protecting Officer Sato.
高木老弟 你去保护佐藤警官
Chiba-kun, you go take care of Ran-kun.
千叶去守着小兰
If there is any problem, report to me.
一有状况立刻向我报告
Yes, sir.
是
Last summer.
去年夏天
Dr. Tomatsu Jinno, the first surgeon of the Touto University Hospital,
东大附属医院第一外科医师
was found dead in his apartment.
仁野保医生被人发现陈尸在自家公寓里
The police officer in charge of this case at that time was my senior,
当时负责调查的是我的学长
Officer Tomonari, who was working with me
和我一同任职于警视厅搜查一课的友成警官
The officers who worked for him at the time were
他的手下就是
Officer Narasawa and Officer Shiba, who were both shot dead,
遭到枪杀的奈良泽警官 芝警官
and Officer Sato.
以及佐藤警官
Dr. Jinno had been drinking too much alcohol.
仁野医生当时喝了不少酒
He took his own scalpel
用自己的手术刀
and cut his right carotid artery.
朝自己右颈动脉一刀切下
At last, he died of blood loss.
最后因失血过多身亡
The first person to find the body
第一个发现尸体的
was his sister, Tamaki Jinno, a correspondent who lived next door to him.
是住在他家隔壁担任通信记者的妹妹仁野环
Uncle Mouri, this woman...
叔叔 这个人
She was at the party at the hotel.
她曾出现在饭店的派对上
I remember now.
我想起来了
She came to find me a while ago.
她不久前曾找过我
What? She came to the agency?
什么 她去过事务所
What did she want with you?
她找你做什么
Well, I was drunk at that time.
这个嘛 当时我已经喝醉了
So I don't remember what she said.
所以她说了什么我全不记得了
But I do remember the murder case of this Dr. Jinno.
我记得这个仁野医生的命案
Just a few days before he died,
他在死亡的前几天
he was sued by the patient's family for surgical errors, right?
曾因手术失误遭患者家属控告对吧
Right.
没错
There was also an apology letter for his surgical errors
他房里的文书处理机内
found in the computer in his room.
也留有为手术失误谢罪的遗书
So the police thought there was a high probability that Dr. Jinno committed suicide.
所以警方认为仁野医生自杀的可能性极高
But his sister didn't think he committed suicide.
但他妹妹却不认为他是自杀
She said her brother was a feckless doctor who didn't care about his patients' lives at all.
她说她哥是个向来不关心患者死活的差劲医生
The idea that he would commit suicide for surgical errors
说他会为手术失误自杀谢罪
was complete nonsense for her.
她根本不相信
About one week before the incident,
大约在一星期前
just in front of a warehouse, she saw Dr. Jinno
她曾在某个仓库前
having an argument with a young man with dyed purple hair.
看见仁野医生与一名头发染成紫色的年轻人发生口角
A man with dyed purple hair?
头发染成紫色的人
Considering the possibility of danger, Officer Tomonari
友成警官为谨慎起见
took Officer Sato, Officer Narasawa and Officer Shiba to the warehouse together.
便带着佐藤 奈良泽与芝警官前往仓库
It was a very hot day.
那天天气特别炎热
It is said the temperature was even over 35 degrees.
据说气温超过35度
The door was locked.
门上锁了
Okay, let's stay put for now.
好 我们暂时按兵不动
Shiba-kun, you go across the street to monitor.
小芝到对面监视
Yes, sir.
是
Why is it so hot?
怎么这么热啊
What happened to you?
您怎么了
Chief!
组长
He's having a heart attack.
他是心脏病发作
Call an ambulance!
快叫救护车
Got it.
是
Don't call.
别打
We're monitoring him now.
我们现在正在监视
But...
可是…
I can handle it.
我挺得住
I'll call a taxi to the hospital myself.
我自己叫计程车去医院
You guys keep watching.
你们继续监视
Sato-kun was worried, so she went after him later.
放不下心的佐藤后来追上一看
Chief Tomonari!
友成组长
So Sato-kun immediately took Officer Tomonari
于是佐藤立即将友成警官
to the Touto University Hospital,
送往东都大学附属医院
but he breathed his last breath in surgery.
可是友成警官却在手术中断了气
Why isn't Officer Sato back yet?
佐藤警官怎么还没回来
Someone's coming.
有人过来了
I've had enough.
受不了
It's too hot today.
今天热死了
Let's roll.
我们上吧
Wait, don't you know who he is?
慢着 你可知他是谁
He's Director Odagiri's son, Toshiya-san.
他是小田切局长的儿子 敏也
In the end, Officer Tomonari died.
最后友成警官不幸身亡
Dr. Jinno's death was ruled a suicide.
仁野医生之死被判定为自杀
The investigation ended here.
调查也就到此结束了
The police also investigated the relationship between his sister Tamakii and Toshiya.
警方也调查过他妹妹小环与敏也的关系
But Officer Shiba said she was not involved in the case.
芝警官表示她与这件案子并无牵连
So that's what this is about.
原来是这么回事
But Officer Tomonari...
但是友成警官
He has an only boy named Makoto.
有个名叫阿真的独生子
He was at the party too.
这个人也有参加派对
What?
什么
But he was gone in the blink of an eye.
不过一下子就不见了
Is there anything wrong with this guy?
这家伙怎么了
They said that night when at the wake...
据说守灵那晚…
Why didn't you call an ambulance?
当时为何不叫救护车
If you had called an ambulance, my father could have been alive.
叫救护车的话 家父也许就能得救
But, Chief...
可是 组长他…
It's you who got my father killed!
是你们杀了我爸
I will never forgive you!
我绝不会原谅你们
Conan-kun, here.
柯南 给你
Thank you.
谢谢
Not long after that, Officer Narasawa and Officer Shiba were transferred.
之后没多久 奈良泽和芝警官就调职了
Until recently, Shiratori found out that
直到最近白鸟才发现
Sato-kun was investigating something when not on duty.
佐藤在执勤以外的时间里还在进行某些调查
Officer Narasawa asked her to join him and Officer Shiba
她受奈良泽警官之托与芝警官三人
to re-investigate the case from a year ago.
重新调查一年前的案子
But Sato-san didn't know
但佐藤并不知道
Toshiya-kun's relationship with Dr. Jinno.
敏也与仁野医生的关系
Officer Narasawa was shot dead
奈良泽警官遭到枪杀
just shortly after he started this investigation.
就是在他开始调查不久之后
Then Officer Shiba was shot dead again.
后来芝警官又遭枪杀
After that, we realized that it was related to the case a year ago.
我们才确定这件事与一年前的案子有关
Judging from the police manual,
我们由警察手册得出
the murderer should be someone related to the police force.
凶手应该是警界相关人士
Takagi started investigating Makoto Tomonari, the son of our chief.
高木开始调查组长之子友成真
I'm in charge of investigating Toshiya-kun, the son of the director.
我负责调查局长之子敏也
I thought there was a possibility that the murderer would attack Sato-kun.
我认为凶手很有可能会攻击佐藤
So I tried to send a man to protect her.
想找人保护她
But she declined my help.
却遭到她的谢绝
So, that's why you found her at the party.
你在聚会上找她就是为了这件事啊
Right.
没错
I figure it out, Inspector Megure.
我明白了 目暮警官
The murderer is Toshiya Odagiri.
凶手就是小田切敏也
Because the three officers, Narasawa, Shiba and Sato,
因为奈良泽 芝 佐藤三位警官
started re-investigating the case from a year ago,
又开始调查一年前的案子
so he struck first.
他才先下手为强
But he didn't shot Sato-kun.
但射击佐藤的人并不是他啊
He didn't test positive for gunshot residues.
他没被测出有硝烟反应
All right, you have a point.
这倒也是
But that Makoto Tomonari
倒是友成真…
are still nowhere to be found.
至今仍下落不明
The day Officer Narasawa and Officer Shiba were shot,
奈良泽以及芝警官中枪之日
he was seen wandering around the scene.
有人看到他在现场附近徘徊
And today, he was at the party again.
今天他又出现在聚会上
All we know is that the murderer is left-handed.
现在只知道凶手是个左撇子
Oh, right. Makoto Tomonari is left-handed!
对了 友成真就是左撇子啊
All right, arrest Makoto Tomonari immediately!
好 立刻通缉友成真
Yes, sir.
是
Inspector Megure.
目暮警官
How was Dr. Jinno's carotid artery cut?
仁野医生的颈动脉是怎么被切断的
How was it cut?
怎么被切断
It was cut straight down from the top right to the bottom left.
由右上朝左下直直切下
If this is a homicide case,
如果这也是他杀案件的话
the murderer might be left-handed too.
凶手也许也是个左撇子
How do you know that?
你怎么知道
Because...
因为
This is to avoid spraying blood on the body.
为了不让血喷到身上
In that case,
这么一来
The murderer can't cut the right carotid artery without using his left hand.
不用左手就无法切断右颈动脉了
Right, Conan-kun?
是这样子吧 柯南
I see, but
原来如此 不过
Makoto Tomonari has nothing to do with Dr. Jinno.
友成真与仁野医生毫无关系
Even if the case of Dr. Jinno is a homicide case,
就算仁野医生真是遭人所杀
the left-handed murderer could have been someone else.
惯用左手的凶手也可能是其他人
Toshiya-san is left-handed too.
敏也也是左撇子
He used his left hand to light the match.
他点火柴用的也是左手
There was another person.
还有一个人
His father, Director Odagiri.
就是他父亲小田切局长
He was also left-handed.
他也是个左撇子
Nonsense! How could the director be the murderer?
胡说 局长怎么可能是凶手
Inspector Megure.
目暮警官
I'm Ayumi Yoshida.
我是吉田步美
This is Genta Kojima, Mitsuhiko Tsuburaya.
这是小岛元太 圆谷光彦
This is Ai Haibara.
这是灰原哀
We are all friends of Conan-kun.
我们都是柯南的朋友
We are here to see you, Ran onee-san.
我们是特地来看望小兰姐你的
Thank you.
谢谢你们
But I'm sorry.
但是 真对不起
I don't remember anyone.
我谁都不记得了
How come? I don't believe it.
怎么会 我不相信
We used to play together before.
我们以前还常在一起玩的
Don't you remember me too?
连我也不记得了吗
I'm Professor Agasa.
我是阿笠博士
I am the genius scientist who lives next door to your childhood friend,
我就是住在和你青梅竹马的工藤新一家隔壁的
Shinichi Kudo.
天才科学家
Shinichi Kudo?
工藤 新一
Do you remember about Shinichi-ni-chan?
你记得新一哥哥的事吗
No, I don't.
不记得
Is that so?
是吗
What's wrong, Haibara?
怎么了 灰原
It seems that someone has been watching us.
好像有人一直在盯着我们看
I guess I'm just being paranoid.
大概是我多心了
I'm sorry, I'm a little tired.
对不起 我有点累了
It's okay, you should get some rest.
没关系 你就好好休息吧
Who is it?
谁
Damn it!
可恶
What's wrong Conan?
怎么了 柯南
Uncle Mouri, is it possible that Ran-nee-chan saw the murder's face
叔叔 小兰姐会不会在佐藤警官中枪时
when Officer Sato got shot?
看到了凶手的长相
What?
什么
If so,
如果真是如此
the murderer may come to kill Ran-nee-chan!
凶手也许会来要小兰的命
You're finally here.
你们终于来了
No need to worry.
你放心吧
Takagi-kun and Chiba-kun will take turns to watch over her.
高木与千叶会轮流看护的
What's the situation now?
现在情况如何
Kogoro is staying with her.
小五郎正在陪她
Okay, let's go.
好 我们走
Kisaki-san.
妃女士
What is it?
什么事
Dr. Kazato wants to talk to you about your daughter's condition.
风户医生想跟你谈谈令嫒的病情
According to the results of the MRI,
根据MRI检查的结果 (MRI：核磁共振成像)
there was no brain damage found.
并未发现脑部有损伤
It seems that your daughter lost her memory
看来令嫒会丧失记忆
because she's trying to avoid the mental trauma.
是想逃避自己精神上受到的创伤
Are you saying that
这么说
if I take my daughter to that hotel
只要带小女到那家饭店
to reenact the scene once, her memory will come back?
将案子重演一次 她就会恢复记忆
What are you talking about?
你在胡说什么
If she doesn't want to remember, then you shouldn't force her to remember.
她不想记起的回忆就不该勉强她想起来
What?
怎么
Do you want Ran to lose her memory forever?
你情愿小兰永远不恢复记忆吗
I will never make her suffer.
我是不会让她受任何折磨的
If we force her to remember,
如果勉强她回想
I'm afraid it will cause damage to her brain.
恐怕会对脑部造成伤害
I told you.
我就说吧
Excuse me.
请等一下
Hello, this is Kazato.
你好 我是风户
Okay, I know. I'll make a call.
好 我知道 我会打电话过去的
If Ran really saw the murder's face,
如果小兰看到凶手的长相
she must regain her memory and identify the murder as soon as possible,
若不尽早让她恢复记忆找出凶手的话
or she may be killed by the murder at any time.
她就随时会有生命危险
But as the doctor said,
但正如医生所言
we can't force her to remember.
又不能勉强她去回想
Then it's up to me to protect Ran.
那只有靠我保护小兰了
Strange, nobody is answering.
奇怪 怎么没人接
I'm sorry for that.
不好意思
Doctor.
医生
Is there any way to bring back her memory naturally?
有没有自然的方法可以让她恢复记忆呢
Generally speaking, in a relaxed state,
一般来说在放松的状态下
sometimes the patient's memory will come back all of a sudden.
患者常会突然恢复记忆
I see.
我明白了
I'll move in with you when Ran gets out of the hospital.
小兰出院后我就搬去跟你们住
What?
什么
That way, I can take care of Ran.
这样我就能照顾小兰
Ran will be more relaxed.
小兰也会放松许多
Are you kidding? I'll be more stressed, okay?
开什么玩笑 那我压力不是更大了
What you're gonna be is none of my business.
你会怎样可不干我的事
It's all for Ran.
这一切都是为了小兰
You won't object, will you?
你不会反对吧
Oh, I'm screwed.
完蛋了
Ran-san, try not to force yourself to recall.
小兰 尽量别勉强自己回想
You understand?
知道吗
Yes.
好
If you remember anything, please contact me.
如果恢复了一点记忆 请与我联络
I will.
我会的
Since you were born,
你出生后
You've lived in this city for 17 years.
在这个城市里住了17年
Do you remember anything?
有没有一点印象
This is your home.
这就是你的家
Mouri Detective Agency?
毛利 侦探事务所
Don't get wet.
当心被淋到雨
What's wrong, Ran?
怎么了 小兰
Maybe she's afraid of puddles.
她大概是讨厌积水吧
When Officer Sato got shot, there was a puddle of water in the toilet too.
佐藤警官中枪的时候 厕所里也有积水
Please move the car forward a bit.
请把车往前开一点
Okay.
好的
This is my office on the second floor.
二楼这里是办公室
I always work on big cases at that desk.
我都是在那张桌子上办大案子的
I'm afraid you just drink beer and watch TV at that desk every day.
我看是每天喝啤酒看电视吧
On the third floor, this is the living room. And this is the kitchen.
三楼这里是客厅 这里是厨房
This is your room.
这是你的房间
This brat is Shinichi Kudo.
这小子叫工藤新一
He is that bastard who used some kind of dirty trick to bewitch you.
是个把你骗得团团转的臭小子
Who used dirty trick to bewitch her?
谁把她骗得团团转了
Ran-nee-chan, you know karate too.
小兰姐 你还会空手道喔
I know karate.
我会空手道
You even won a provincial high school competition.
你还获得过高中省立大赛的优胜呢
Remember?
记得吗
No.
不记得了
Okay.
是吗
But don't worry.
不过你们不用担心
I'll remember soon.
我很快就会想起来的
That's right. Anyway, you finally got out of the hospital,
说得也是 为了庆祝你出院
we should have a big dinner tonight.
今晚就吃点好料理吧
Then I guess I'll have to show off my excellent cooking skills this time.
那就让我偶尔施展一下烹饪技巧吧
What's wrong with you two?
你们两个怎么了
Well, your cooking...
你煮的东西…
You don't have to bother cooking for me.
不用准备我那份了
I'm not really hungry.
我并不是很饿
You're being too polite, Conan-kun.
你就别跟我客气了 柯南
I promise you I'll do my best
阿姨一定会拿出看家本领
to make the most delicious beef broth ever.
做出最好吃的牛肉浓汤的
That's what I'm afraid of.
那才恐怖呢
Honey, where are you going?
老公 你要上哪去
Nothing.
不是的
I forgot that my neighbor is waiting for me to play mahjong tonight.
我忘了今晚已经约了邻居打麻将
Our daughter is sick like this.
女儿都病成这样
How can you go play mahjong at this point?
你还有心情去打麻将
Are you suggesting that
难不成你是在暗示
my cooking is unpalatable to you?
我煮的菜让你难以下咽
Great.
太好了
Ran is livelier than I thought.
小兰比我想像的还要开朗
She should be fine.
这样就没事了
Ran.
兰
You want to be my bodyguards?
你们要当我的贴身保镖
Officer Takagi said that the murderer might hurt you.
高木警官说凶手可能会对你不利
We, Detective Boys,
我们少年侦探团
have decided to protect your safety.
已经决定保护小兰姐的安全了
Now our team name is changed to
现在改名叫
"Ran-nee-chan's Guards".
「小兰姐护卫队」
I have a pepper spray gun with me.
我带了辣椒水枪
I have a boomerang.
我有回力镖
I have handcuffs.
我带了手铐
Come on, that's all kid stuff.
拜托 那些可全是骗小孩子的玩意儿
Thank you.
谢谢你们
I feel so much more safe.
我觉得安心多了
Let me buy you some drinks as a thank you.
我请你们喝饮料作为答谢吧
Let's go upstairs.
上楼吧
Okay!
好
Great!
太棒了
She still doesn't remember anything?
她还是什么都没想起来
No.
是啊
Wouldn't it be better for you
她就这样别再想起过去
if she just lost her memory of the past forever?
对工藤你而言不是更好
You would no longer worry that you might be exposed.
你就不用再担心身份会曝光了
How can you say that?
你说什么
If it were me...
如果是我
I'd rather forget the past, if I could.
可以的话 倒宁可失去记忆
Including my sister's murder and the fact that I was an organization member who made poison.
姐姐被杀以及我成为组织一员制造毒药的事
If I could forget all this,
如果都能忘了
and live the rest of my life as this pupil named Ai Haibara, I would definitely be very happy.
做个单纯的小学生灰原哀不知该有多好
Then,
然后
I could be with you forever...
就能跟你永远
Forever.
永远这样
Haibara, you...
灰原 你
I'm just kidding. You're now in your right mind?
开玩笑的 有点精神了吗
Hi, kid.
小不点
Is this your new girlfriend?
你新交的女朋友吗
Now the nagging witch shows up again.
啰嗦的家伙又来了
This is a picture of you winning the karate competition.
这是你在空手道大赛中获胜的照片
Do you remember?
还记得吗
This person...
这个人
You mean Kudo?
你说工藤啊
He's your husband.
他是你老公
Who are you calling husband?
老公你个头啦
She seems to remember.
她好像有印象
Really, Ran-nee-chan?
真的吗 小兰姐
No.
没有
But...
不过
Somehow, I kind of feel like I'm missing him.
好像有种很怀念的感觉
I don't know why.
我也不知道为什么
You might remember if you see Shinichi-san.
见了新一哥哥你也许就想起来了
That's right! You should bring him here!
没错 你快带他来
If I could have found him, I would have brought him here long ago.
如果能带他来的话就不用这么辛苦了
By the way, that high school detective
对了 那个高中生侦探
is working on the most difficult cases nationwide, right?
正在侦办全国的疑难案件 对吧
That bastard!
那个死家伙
Ran is suffering now. Where the hell is he?
小兰现在在受苦 他到底跑到哪去了
Come in.
请进
Ran-nee-chan, I've run a bath for you.
小兰姐 去洗澡吧
Thank you.
谢谢你
Conan-kun.
柯南
What kind of person is Shinichi Kudo?
工藤新一是个怎样的人
What kind of person?
怎样的人
I guess
我想
he is the kind of person who always puts you first
他是把小兰姐放在第一位
but doesn't know how to directly express his feelings.
却又无法明白表示的那种人吧
I really want to see him.
真想见见那个人
Ran, do you want to go to Ginza tomorrow?
小兰 明天要不要去银座
I can't help getting mad when I see that old bastard.
有那死老头在我就想发火
Let's go shopping for clothes and relax.
我们去散散心买衣服买个过瘾
Will you join us, Conan-kun?
柯南也一起去吧
Okay.
好
Are you okay?
不要紧吧
Officer Sato!
佐藤警官
Officer Sato! Hang in there!
佐藤警官 振作点
Thank you, sir. I'm sorry.
谢谢 不好意思 我
Damn it!
可恶
The tram is coming!
电车来了
Ran!
兰
She just fell asleep on sedatives.
她刚打了镇静剂睡着了
Is Ran okay?
小兰没事吧
Luckily, she only got some scratches.
还好只受了点擦伤
But after this incident,
但是经过这个事件
I'm afraid it will affect the recovery of her memory.
对她恢复记忆恐怕会有影响
Takagi, wasn't you supposed to watch over her?
高木 你是怎么看人的
I'm so sorry!
对不起
But now things are clear.
不过 这下就清楚了
The moment Sato-kun got shot,
小兰一定是在佐藤中枪时
Ran-kun must have seen the murderer's face.
看到了凶手的长相
Listen, no matter what happen, you must protect Ran-kun.
听好 无论如何都要保护小兰的安全
Yes, sir!
是
It's not enough just to protect her.
光是保护还不够
We must strike first.
我们必须主动出击
(Beika Sun Plaza Hotel)
「米花太阳广场饭店」
All the people who were in the hotel at that time test positive for gunshot residues.
当时留在饭店里的人全都未测出硝烟反应
Is it really impossible to fire a gun
开枪而不留下硝烟反应
without leaving gunshot residue particles?
真的是不可能的吗
Wait a minute.
等等
I remember
我记得当时
the umbrella stand was locked at that time.
伞架的扣环是锁住的
After the crime,
案发之后
the umbrella stand was open,
扣环松了
and the umbrella was not in its original place.
而且伞也不在原位了
Plus Ran's reaction when she left the hospital.
还有小兰出院的时候
Could it be...
难道说
What? That's your umbrella?
什么 那把伞是你的
Do you know where it is now?
你知道那伞现在在哪吗
I'm sorry.
不好意思
It had a hole in it, so I just threw it away.
因为上面有个洞 姐姐就把它丢了
Not surprising. After all, it's been so long.
说得也是 都过了这么久了
I'm just kidding. I kept it for you.
骗你的 我帮你保存得好好的
That's funny.
喂喂
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm right.
果然没错
I finally figured out
终于找到了
the way to shoot without leaving gunshot residues.
不留下硝烟反应的射击方法
Now, in addition to Makoto Tomonari,
这么一来除了友成真 仁野环 连敏也也有可能
No, everyone at the party could be a possible suspect.
不 参加宴会的所有人都有嫌疑
Found it.
就是这里
I see.
我懂了
Tamaki-san went to the party
小环小姐会到宴会会场
Because she was following Toshiya-san.
其实是去跟踪敏也的
Damn bitch!
臭女人
Why do you follow me every day?
为什么每天都跟着我
Do you care?
你在意吗
What?
什么
I'll find evidence for the two officers you shot
我会替遭你射杀的那两名警官
to prove that you're the killer!
找出你杀人的证据
Are you trying to use yourself as bait?
你想拿自己作诱饵
You're Dr. Jinno's sister, Tamaki-san, right?
姐姐是仁野医生的妹妹小环吧
The man who had an argument with your brother a year ago
一年前与你哥哥发生口角的人
is Toshiya Odagiri.
就是小田切敏也
You must have found out that because his father was the director,
你一定是查到因为他老爸是局长
he didn't even need to give a statement, right?
所以他连笔录都没做对吧
Who are you, kid?
小弟弟 你是谁
Conan Edogawa.
江户川柯南
A detective.
是个侦探
Detective?
侦探
If you really love your brother that much,
如果你真的深爱你哥哥的话
naturally, you must hate the three officers
对于将你哥哥以自杀结案的那三名警官
who closed your brother's case with suicide.
自然会深恶痛绝吧
I hate my brother.
我恨死了我哥哥
The only reason I'm investigating this case
我之所以会调查这个案件
is to find out the truth.
只是想知道真相罢了
Then why don't you take a risk to sneak into the enemy's base camp.
那你大可孤注一掷 直捣敌人的大本营
(House of Director Odagiri)
「小田切警视长家」
He's using iaido to test the sword?
这是居合流刀法的试刀
Impressive.
厉害
You're Tamaki Jinno, right?
你是仁野环吧
I have something for you.
我有东西要给你
Something for me?
给我
One month ago,
这是一个月前
I found this in my son, Toshiya's room.
在小犬敏也房内找到的
T.JINNO.
T.JINNO
This is my brother's thing.
这是我哥哥的
Yes.
没错
One year ago, Officer Tomonari died suddenly of a heart attack.
一年前友成警官因心脏病猝死
This was the last case he worked on.
这是他侦办的最后一件案子
That's why I remembered this name.
所以我记得这个名字
I asked Toshiya about it.
在我询问敏也之后
He told me he learned that Dr. Jinno was selling forbidden drugs,
他说他得知仁野医生私自贩售禁药
so he took this opportunity to extort hush money from him.
便以此为由向他勒索遮口费
But there was no mention of Toshiya's name
但是当时的调查资料
in the investigation report at that time.
完全未提及敏也的名字
So I ordered Officer Narasawa to re-investigate this case.
所以我命令奈良泽警官重新调查此案
So the person who ordered him to re-investigate was you, Director Odagiri?
命他重新调查此案的是小田切局长你
Since Officer Narasawa was shot dead,
奈良泽警官遭人射杀后
Inspector Megure has taken over this case.
现在由目暮警官接办
But if it was Officer Narasawa who first proposed to reopen this case,
但如果重新调查此案是出于奈良泽警官自己意思的话
perhaps you'd try to stop him from investigating your own son.
也许你就会防止他调查到自己儿子身上了
I do have motive to kill them three.
我的确有杀他们三人的动机
If you really want the truth to come out,
既然你真的想让真相大白
show me the investigation report.
那就给我看调查资料
That's impossible.
这不可能
Letting the truth come out
让真相大白
is police work.
是我们警方的工作
Thank god! You didn't get hurt.
你没受伤真是太好了
Thank you.
谢谢
The doctor also said I can be discharged from the hospital now.
医生也说我可以出院了
Sonoko-san.
园子小姐
Just call me Sonoko!
哎哟 叫我园子就行了
What kind of kid is Conan-kun?
柯南是一个怎样的小孩
Why would he risk his life to save me?
他为什么会拼了命来救我
For a kid, he does seem a little too resourceful.
就孩子来说他的确是非常机灵
He also has a keen sense of the situation. He's great anyway.
感觉也很敏锐 很神就对了
But if you ask my opinion,
不过真要我说呢
I'd say that he's just an arrogant kid.
不过是个狂妄的小鬼罢了
Is that so?
是吗
In this year's Tropical Land,
今年热带乐园中
there will be a new area named "Pangea Wild Island".
又增加了「野生太古岛」
I believe it'll bring more fun to you.
肯定能给游客带来更大的乐趣
I know that place.
我 知道那个地方
You mean this Tropical Land?
你说这个热带乐园
Oh right, you used to go there with Shinichi-kun.
对了 你和新一一起去过
I see.
原来如此
Ran-san's memory is much better than before.
小兰的记忆的确恢复了很多
Doctor.
医生
If she goes to the Tropical Land,
如果到热带乐园
will her memory come back?
她的记忆能恢复吗
It's possible.
的确有这个可能
I'll go there tomorrow and see if there will be any change.
我明天就去看看
Wait, I object.
慢着 我反对
The murderer might try to hurt you again.
凶手说不定还想加害于你
Indeed, it's painful for me to recall that case.
想起那件案子 会给自己带来痛苦的
To be honest, I'm also afraid to think about it.
说实话我也很怕想起那件案子
But I can't go on like this.
但这样下去也不是办法
I have to take the first step.
我总得主动踏出第一步
Ran.
小兰
Ran-san, you're so brave.
小兰真勇敢
With this thought, I believe you'll be fine in the Tropical Land.
你能这么想 就算去热带乐园也不会有事的
Then how about we go there the day after tomorrow.
那就后天再去吧
I won't be available tomorrow.
明天我实在抽不开身
Don't worry, I'll be with our daughter.
别担心 我会陪女儿的
I will protect Ran well, even if I die!
就算拼了我这条老命也会保护好兰的
Dear...
老公
Ran, I'll go with you too.
小兰 我也陪你去
Thank you.
谢谢
But, don't let Conan-kun know about this.
不过 这件事别告诉柯南
If he knew, he'd definitely go with us.
如果告诉他的话 他一定会跟着去的
I don't want to put him in danger again.
我不想再让他遇到危险了
I see.
知道了
I didn't expect it to be so late.
没想到会弄到这么晚
Conan-kun, if you want to see the investigation report,
柯南 你若想看调查资料
I have a copy.
我那里有复印件
Really?
真的
I'm a journalist after all.
我毕竟是个记者
That copy is in my apartment. I'll bring it to you tomorrow.
资料在我公寓里 明天再拿给你吧
Okay.
好
I'm leaving.
我走了
He's gone.
走了 走了
He didn't notice anything wrong.
没察觉到不对劲
Then we should get going too.
那我们也出发了
Great! Ran-nee-san is out!
太好了 小兰姐出门了
After waiting all morning, we didn't waste our time.
一大早来埋伏总算有收获
Don't we inform Edogawa-kun?
不通知江户川吗
It's okay not to tell him just this once. He was ahead of us every time.
偶尔一次没关系啦 我们每次都被他抢先
Let me be clear, don't take any risks.
说好了 你们可不能冒险
Follow the car in front.
跟着前面的车
Did you find out anything, little detective?
看出什么了吗 小侦探
The manual that Officer Shiba was holding...
芝警官握着的这本手册
What's wrong with that manual?
那本手册怎么了
If the manual was taken out of his breast pocket,
如果是从胸口拿出来的话
the direction of the manual should be reversed, shouldn't it
手册不是应该反方向吗
If he took it out of the pocket...
从口袋里拿出来的话
Indeed.
真的耶
Maybe
也许
the person who pulled out the manual wasn't Officer Shiba, but the murderer.
抽出手册的不是芝警官 而是凶手
I see. It's possible.
原来如此 也有这个可能
I'll find the evidence.
我会找出证据的
Aren't you right-handed, Tamaki-san?
小环姐不是右撇子吗
I was left-handed before I changed to right-handed.
我原本是左撇子后来才改成右手的
So when I think about other things,
所以在边想事边抽烟的时候
I will unconsciously use my left hand to smoke.
就会不自觉地用左手了
Unconsciously?
不自觉
Come to think of it, at that time...
这么一说 我记得那个时候
Wait a minute.
慢着
That... That means...
那么 那个是…
Could it be...
难道说
That's what he meant!
那是这个意思
The hospital where your brother used to work
你哥哥以前工作的地方
is the Touto University Hospital, right?
是东都大学附属医院吧
Right. Sorry, Conan-kun.
没错 抱歉 柯南
I've got to go.
我有点事得走了
Maybe we should call it a day.
今天就先到这里了
Bye, Conan-kun.
再见 柯南
Take me to the Tropical Land.
到热带乐园
Yes!
好
I remember this place.
我 记得这个地方
I remember when Shinichi came here with you,
我记得新一和你来这里时
we solved the Roller Coaster Murder Case.
曾破了云霄飞车杀人事件
Let's try this roller coaster too.
那我们也去坐坐吧
Maybe you'll remember more.
说不定能想起更多的事情
The Mystery Roller Coaster
神秘云霄飞车是在
is on the Magical Fantasy Island nearby.
隔壁的「神奇幻想岛」上
Ran and Sonoko, you two sit in the front.
小兰你们坐前面
You know what?
你知道吗
I'm sure Conan Doyle will say that.
柯南道尔一定会这么说
It's nothing
没什么
Ran onee-san and the others are over there.
小兰姐他们在那边
I want to play too.
我也好想坐
What are you saying?
你在说什么呢
We should check around to see if there are any suspicious people nearby.
我们得趁机看看附近有没有可疑分子
Let's go.
走吧
Okay.
好
Strange. Isn't Mouri-kun afraid of heights?
怪了 毛利不是有恐高症吗
I'm dying!
完了
Well, are you all right?
这个 不要紧吧
Ran, do you want a Coke?
小兰 要不要喝可乐
Yeah.
好的
Baby bear balloons!
熊宝宝气球
Who on earth invented that stupid thing?
真是的 是谁发明那玩意儿的
Take it, you must be thirsty.
来 你一定渴了吧
Here's your Coke.
你的可乐
Thank you.
谢谢
Are you Shinichi Kudo?
你就是工藤新一
But I still don't remember who you are.
但我还是想不起你是谁
Mouri-san, I gotta go to the bathroom.
毛利先生 我去方便一下
Thank you!
谢谢
The balloons flew away.
气球飞走了
Ran-san, dangerous!
小兰姐 危险
Stop!
站住
Hey, don't go!
你们几个 别去啊
I won't let you run away!
你逃不掉的
Take that! My pepper spray gun!
看我辣椒水枪的厉害
Makoto Tomonari! It's you!
你是友成真
What did you take?
你带了什么
A knife?
刀
Makoto Tomonari! You're under arrest for attempted murder!
友成真 我现在以杀人未遂的罪名逮捕你
Great!
太好了
Ran-nee-chan's Guards!
小兰姐护卫队
Great victory!
大胜利
Mouri-san!
毛利先生
I'll take him straight back to the police station.
我直接带他回总部了
Wait, I'll go with you!
慢着 我跟你去
Great!
太好了
No one will hurt you anymore.
不会再有人攻击你了
Without me here, you'll think about Shinichi more often, right?
我这老爸不在 你会比较容易想起新一吧
Dad...
爸 爸
It's okay.
没关系
You can wait until you remember it all before calling me that.
等你全想起来了 再叫吧
Thanks to the Detective Boys, Ran is fine.
这次多亏少年侦探团相助
You kids did a great job.
你们立了一件大功
He said we did a great job.
他说我们立了大功
We were complimented
被名侦探
by the famous detective.
夸奖了呢
Okay! We can have fun now!
好 我们可以玩个过瘾了
I want to see the parade!
我想看游行
Can we play into the night, Professor?
可以玩到晚上吗 博士
Okay.
好吧
Shinichi and Ran-kun also played into the night at that time.
新一和小兰那时候也是呆到晚上的
Great!
太好了
Is this really over?
事情真的就此结束了吗
Ran, let's go to the Devil's Laboratory!
小兰 我们去恶魔实验室吧
It's fun!
很好玩哦
(Touto University Hospital) Kid, you are the assistant
小弟弟 你就是那个名侦探
of that famous detective Kogoro Mouri, right?
毛利小五郎的助手
If I help you,
如果我帮你的忙
will you get Mouri-san's autograph for me?
你能帮我要到毛利先生的签名吗
And me.
我也要
No problem.
没问题
How hard can it be? Uncle Mouri's autographs are more than you can imagine.
这有何难 叔叔的签名要多少有多少
Speaking of Dr. Jinno,
说起仁野医生
all I know is he was a nasty doctor.
我只有一句话 是个让人讨厌的医生
That's right.
没错
He only cared about embezzling money, not practicing medicine.
只会贪污钱财根本没医术
He often made errors while performing surgeries.
动手术常常捅娄子
Do you remember?
你还记得吗
Once, while dealing with a patient having a heart attack,
有个患者心脏病发作被送来
he even slashed the wrist of the doctor who was performing the surgery together.
他竟然割到一起执刀的医生的手腕
Right, right.
就是说啊
And he got that patient killed.
还害得那名患者丧了命
Can you tell me more about it?
能说得详细点吗
Just as I expected.
果然不出我所料
I gotta inform Uncle Mouri as soon as possible.
我得尽快通知叔叔
Hello, this is Mouri Detective Agency.
喂 这里是毛利侦探事务所
The famous detective Kogoro Mouri is busy working on a big case.
名侦探毛利小五郎 目前正在侦办大案子
Damn it!
可恶
Hello, this is Kisaki Law Office.
妃法律事务所 你好
It's Conan
我是柯南
Conan-kun?
柯南
Is Miss Kisaki here?
妃律师在吗
Miss Kisaki just got out of court. She's already on her way to Tropical Land.
律师刚刚才下法庭 已经往热带乐园去了
Tropical Land?
热带乐园
I heard that Ran-san is there.
听说小兰人在那里
No!
完了
It's a ghost!
鬼出现了
Alright? Can you talk now?
怎么样 能说话了吧
I got a call from a man.
我接到一个男人打来的电话
He said he'd tell me the truth about my father's death.
他说要告诉我父亲死亡的真相
So I waited for him at the traffic light in Beika Town as he asked.
我按约到米花町的红绿灯下等他
But that man didn't show up,
但那男的并未出现
and Officer Narasawa got killed nearby.
奈良泽警官却在附近遇害了
When I got home,
等我回到家又接到了
I got another call from that man.
那男人打来的电话
He asked me to go to the Midoridai Park Building.
他要我到绿台公园大厦
The man still didn't show up.
但是那个男的还是没出现
But in the parking lot near the building,
在那幢大厦附近的停车场里
Officer Shiba was found shot dead.
却发现了被射杀的芝警官
That's when I realized
这时我才意识到
I was set up by the murderer.
我被凶手设计了
I had to stay at a commercial hotel that night.
当晚我只好住在商业旅馆
The next day, I called home to check my voice mail.
第二天打电话回家查询语音留言
I found a woman who called herself Officer Sato
结果有个自称佐藤警官的女人
asked me to meet her at the Beika Sun Plaza Hotel.
叫我到米花太阳广场饭店见她
She said that if I didn't go, I would be arrested on suspicion of murder.
还说我若不去的话就要以涉嫌杀人的罪名逮捕我
When I went there, I realized that there were police officers everywhere,
我一去才发现 到处都是警方的人
so I left immediately.
我便立刻离开了
But, I never thought Officer Sato would also...
不过 没想到佐藤警官也…
Why didn't you call the police right away?
你为何不立刻通知警方
After my father's incident, how can I possibly trust the police?
经过我父亲那件事后我才不相信警方
Then I wanted to ask Detective Mouri for help.
后来我想求助于毛利侦探
That's why I wandered around his house.
才在他家附近徘徊
So you weren't trying to get close to Ran-kun at Tropical Land?
这么说你在热带乐园 不是想接近小兰
Yes.
对
I just wanted to talk to Mouri-san.
我只是想找毛利先生说话
Wait, how do you explain your knife?
慢着 你明明带了刀子
It was for protecting myself. I was afraid the murderer would hurt me.
那是为了防身 我怕凶手会加害于我
So, the murderer is someone else?
这么说 凶手另有其人
And there is a female accomplice.
而且还有个女共犯
Ran is in danger...
小兰有危险
(Ice Mist Maze)
(冰雾迷宫)
This spot should work.
对了 这里应该可以
Is the observation deck vacant now?
了望台现在空着吗
Yes, because everyone is watching the parade outside.
是啊 因为大家都在看游行
Thank you.
谢谢
Welcome to the Ice Mist Maze.
欢迎来到冰雾迷宫
Where are you, Ran? Where are you?
小兰你在哪 在哪
Genta and the other kids? They're here too?
是元太他们 他们也来了
Then Ran must be around.
那么兰一定在附近
It's him!
是他
Ran!
兰
Right, the Detective Boys Badge!
对了 用侦探团徽章
Genta, Mitsuhiko, Ayumi!
元太 光彦 步美
Can you hear me? Answer me!
听得到吗 回答我
Conan-kun, I can hear you.
柯南 听得到
Conan, guess where we are.
柯南 你猜我们现在在哪
Don't be shocked when I tell you.
听了别吓到哦
We're in Tropical Land.
我们在热带乐园
You guys, calm down and listen to me.
你们冷静听我说
Now the murderer is aiming a pistol at Ran.
现在凶手正用手枪瞄准小兰
What?
什么
Anyway, you must try to walk in the crowd,
总之你们尽量往人多的地方走
and get Ran out of Tropical Land!
快点带小兰离开热带乐园
Hey, are you listening?
喂 你们在听吗
Ran onee-san, run!
小兰姐 快逃
A gun is aimed at you!
有枪在瞄准你
Dangerous!
危险
Professor!
博士
It's me... I put the people around me in danger.
都是我 害了周围的人
Don't leave, Ran-kun.
你别离开 小兰
Don't be alone. That's exactly what the murder wants.
你一落单就正中凶手的下怀了
Ran-kun! Ran-kun!
小兰 小兰
Damn it!
可恶
Ran is in the "Fairy Tale Island" nearby.
小兰在隔壁的「梦幻童话岛」
If I want to go there...
要到那里的话…
Please get aboard.
下一位请上船
Hey, kid!
喂 小弟弟
Over there!
在那里
Conan-kun?
柯南
It's alright now, Ran-nee-chan.
已经没事了 小兰姐
Let's blend in with the crowd and go out.
我们混入人群出去吧
This way!
这边
Shit!
可恶
To kill Ran, he has completely disregarded the other people now.
他为了杀小兰根本不顾旁人
Help! There's a strange man here!
救命啊 这里有个怪人
Get on the boat!
快逃上船
You two!
你们两个
Conan-kun, where did you learn how to drive the boat?
柯南 你是在哪学会开船的
My father taught me in Hawaii.
我爸在夏威夷教过我
I think we're safe now, right?
应该没事了吧
Not yet.
还没
My Coke...
可乐中弹了
Coke?
可乐
20 minutes to 9:00.
9点差20分钟
Conan-kun, a waterfall in front!
柯南 前面是瀑布
Hold on tight!
抓紧了
Go!
快走
Almost there. Come on!
还差一点点 加油
Damn, he's already come.
可恶 他已经追来了
Anyway, we gotta climb up and hide behind the rock!
总之先爬上去躲到岩石的后面
Hurry up!
动作快
Conan-kun?
柯南
This place will be closed at night, no one will come. You can show your face.
这里晚上会关闭 没有人会来 你不用怕露脸
You're really cautious.
你还真够谨慎的
But it's no use hiding.
不过再藏也没用了
I already know the true meaning of Officer Narasawa's message.
我已经知道奈良泽警官 所传达的讯息的真正含义了
The purpose of his clutching his left chest before he died
他在临死前之所以紧抓左胸
was not to suggest the police manual,
并不是想暗示警察手册
but to suggest the heart,
而是心脏
which means one word of the term "department of cardiology",
也就是「心疗科」其中一个字
"cardiology".
「心」
Am I right?
没错吧
Dr. Kyosuke Kazato.
风户京介医生
When did you know it was me?
你什么时候知道是我的
The first time you aroused my suspicion
最初引起我怀疑的
was when you made the call.
是在你打电话的时候
A right-handed person doesn't dial with the left hand.
惯用右手的人不会用左手拨号
So, you're actually left-handed.
所以 你惯用的其实是左手
I see. I didn't notice that.
原来如此 这是我疏忽了
Seven years ago, you were the youngest top surgeon
七年前你在东都大学附属医院
in the Touto University Hospital.
曾享有最年轻的头号外科医师的封号
But during an operation with Dr. Jinno,
但在一次与仁野医生共同执刀的手术中
Dr. Jinno slashed your left wrist by mistake.
仁野医生误将你的左手手腕割伤
After that accident,
经过那次事故
you lost the famous "golden left hand" you were most proud of.
你那著名的黄金左手就此报废
You are a proud person, so you decided to give up being a surgeon,
向来心高气傲的你放下手术刀
and transferred from department of surgery to department of cardiology
从外科转向心疗科
Since then, perhaps because of your pride,
之后 也许是自尊心作祟
you have stopped using your left hand and only used your right hand, right?
你便不再使用左手而一直只用右手 对吧
You're right.
没错
I never thought you'd be able to see through me just by dialing the number.
没想到光是拨号就被你看穿了
After you transferred to Beika Yakushi Hospital
你以心疗科医师的身份
as a cardiologist,
转到米花药师野医院后
you got in touch with Dr. Jinno again one year ago.
一年前与仁野医生又有了纠葛
We happened to meet again.
我们碰巧再度相逢
He invited me to his apartment for a drink.
他请我到他公寓里喝酒
Under the influence of alcohol,
我在酒意驱使下终于提出这六年来心中的疑问
I asked him if that accident was intentional.
我问他当年的事故是不是故意的
You're too slow to understand, aren't you?
你就是太老实了
As I expected, he had arranged the accident on purpose.
果然那次事故是他刻意安排的
At that point, I wanted him dead.
我就是在那时萌生了杀意
Coincidentally, he was accused of surgical error.
他正好被人控告手术失误
There was a good reason for him to commit suicide.
有充分的动机自杀
In the end, his death was ruled a suicide, just as I expected.
最后警方果然以自杀结案
But you should know that someone ordered to re-investigate the case.
但你应该知道有人下令重新调查此案
I heard about it from Officer Narasawa,
我是从调往米花警局的奈良泽警官那里得知的
After the death of his colleague, Officer Tomonari,
他在同事友成警官去世后
he was traumatized and came to consult me.
精神上受创 便来向我咨询
In the course of my treatment, I learned that Makoto Tomonari hated the police.
我在治疗过程中得知友成真对警察深恶痛绝
When you heard that the case would be re-investigated,
你得知此案将重新调查
you decided to kill the three police officers
便想在警方找到你之前
before the police found you.
先解决三名警官
In order to set Makoto Tomonari up to take the fall for you,
为了让友成真替你背黑锅
you asked him out to the crime scenes.
你还将他约到现场
Yes.
没错
When dealing with Officer Narasawa and Officer Shiba,
对付奈良泽和芝警官时
I used my own voice to make the call.
我用自己的声音打电话
When dealing with Officer Sato,
对付佐藤警官时
you edited the tapes you recorded while treating female patients.
你就把替女患者治疗时保存下来的录音带加以剪辑
Right?
对吧
Exactly.
没错
Officer Narasawa was clutching the police manual on his chest before he died.
奈良泽警官死前抓着胸口的警察手册
You heard this from Officer Shiratori, right?
你是从白鸟警官那里听说的吧
That's because I'm his attending physician.
因为我是他的主治医师
In order to suggest that the murderer is the son of a police officer, Makoto Tomonari,
你又为了让人联想到警察之子友成真
after Officer Shiba fell to the ground,
便在芝警官倒地之后
you put the police manual into his hand.
将警察手册放到他手上
You are really something, Conan-kun.
你真厉害 柯南
Too bad you don't have proof that I'm the murderer.
可惜你没证据证明我是凶手
Because after Officer Sato got shot,
因为佐藤警官中枪时
I didn't test positive for gunshot residues.
警方并未测出我有硝烟反应
Speaking of this little trick,
这个手法
I'll be glad to explain it to you, if you really want to hear.
如果你想听 我就解释给你听
But only after you've been arrested by the police.
不过得在你被警方逮捕之后
This way.
走这边
He'll be waiting at that exit.
他一定会在那个出口埋伏
(Adventure Island)
「冒险开拓岛」
This is...
这里是
This is the main island of "Adventure Island".
是「冒险开拓岛」的本岛
There is an underwater tunnel from that island to here.
从那个小岛经过海底通到了这里
Is that so?
原来如此
Let's go.
走吧
I haven't finished yet.
我还没把话说完呢
Damn it, did he come after us by boat?
可恶 他划船追过来了
I'll be totally screwed if you really see through that trick.
那个手法要是被你识破就糟了
I'll be one of the suspects in Officer Sato's murder.
我会成为射击佐藤警官的嫌疑犯之一
Even if Ran says that you're the murder,
即使小兰证明凶手是你
you can still use that test to play the innocent.
你也打算以没硝烟反应装傻
You're right.
你说对了
Although Ran-kun only took a quick look at me,
虽然小兰只看到我一眼
I can't take any chances.
不过我不会冒任何风险
But I'd like to see if your reasoning is accurate.
我倒要听听看 你的推理准不准
As you wish.
可以
At first, you cut off the power supply on the 15th floor of the hotel.
你先让饭店十五楼停电
Then, you put on your surgical gloves,
然后带上手术用的手套
grabbed the umbrella you put in the umbrella stand and run to the ladies' room.
拿起事先放在伞架上的伞 跑到女厕所
The front of the umbrella has a hole that you broke in advance.
你又事先在伞的前端挖了洞
You put the pistol through the hole before shooting.
将手枪穿过那个洞再进行射击
This way, the umbrella blocked the gunpowder and smoke.
也就是说伞挡住了火药和硝烟
That's why you didn't test positive for gunshot residues at that night.
所以那时才没测出你有硝烟反应
I believe you've already flushed the gloves down the toilet.
手套恐怕已被你在男厕所里冲掉了
Exactly correct, Conan-kun.
完全正确 柯南
Seems like I have no choice but to kill you.
看来我真的得让你去死了
Conan-kun.
柯南
Why?
为什么
Why would you risk your life to protect me?
为什么 你会拼了命来保护我
I like you.
喜欢你
Because I like you.
因为我喜欢你
More than anyone else on this planet.
比这地球上的任何一个人都要喜欢
Jump!
快跳
Take a deep breath. Quickly.
用力吸口气 快点
Thank you.
谢谢你
Little man.
小大人
Damn it!
可恶
(Science Island)
「科学宇宙岛」
46 seconds left.
还差46秒
He's coming!
他来了
Let's end it here, Conan-kun!
我们就在这里了结吧 柯南
You have no place to run.
你们已经无路可逃了
Conan-kun!
柯南
I'm fine. Just scratched my arm.
我没事 只是擦伤了手臂
I told you. You have no place to run.
我说过 你们无路可逃了
If you kill Ran here,
你要是在这里杀了小兰
that will prove that Makoto Tomonari is innocent.
不就证明友成真是无辜的吗
You have a point.
说得也是
I was planning to kill him before Makoto Tomonari was arrested.
我本想在友成真被捕前解决他
Change of plans.
没办法
I think it's better to put ladies first.
我看 还是女士优先吧
5.
这是哪种咒语吗
Ran-san, put it down!
小兰 快放下
Officer Sato!
佐藤警官
Take it, you must be thirsty.
来 你一定渴了吧
Stay away!
离我远一点
Once the fountain is over, you'll be dead.
水一喷完就结束了
You'd better give up!
你们死心吧
Kid stuff.
骗小孩子的把戏
There he is.
就是那里
Go to hell!
去死吧
Conan-kun.
柯南
Ran, are you...
小兰 难道说…
Little brat, I'll kill you first!
可恶 我就先拿你开刀
No...no way!
不…不会吧
I remembered everything.
我全想起来了
Including the scene where you shot Officer Sato,
包括你射击佐藤警官的那一幕
and the fact that I won the karate competition championship!
和我获得空手道大赛优胜的事
Karate?
空手道
Championship?
优胜
Impressive.
好厉害
Ran!
兰
Mom! Dad!
妈妈 爸爸
You...
你…
Your memory has come back?
你恢复记忆了
So you remember me too?
那你也记得我咯
Of course I do.
当然
You're Sonoko Suzuki, my best friend for life.
你是铃木园子 我一生的好友
Ran!
小兰
Ran! Thank god!
小兰 太好了
So this guy is the killer!
凶手果然是这家伙
Director Odagiri ordered to re-investigate this case himself.
小田切局长自己下令重新调查
He already told us.
他已经告诉我们了
Conan, you are so cunning!
柯南 你好狡猾
You always catch the murderer yourself.
就知道自己抓凶手
Don't be so childish. It's because he didn't want you in danger.
什么话 他是不想连累你们
But we're a team, aren't we?
这也太见外了
We are all members of the Detective Boys.
我们都是少年侦探团的
Sorry, sorry.
抱歉抱歉
Conan-kun, you're bleeding.
柯南 你流血了
Here.
给
Everything is fine now. That's great.
太好了 总算没事了
Yes.
是啊
You did an amazing job, great detective.
这可是大功一件哦 名侦探
What are you doing here, Tamaki-san?
小环姐 你怎么在这里
Toshiya is having a concert here. I'm here to spy on him.
我来监视在这里开演唱会的敏也
Looks like I wasted my efforts.
不过 全是白费力气
Then again...
话说回来
Who said "I will protect Ran well, even if I die"?
什么「我拼死也会保护小兰」
It's Conan-kun and Professor Agasa who risked their lives to protect Ran, all right?
拼死保护小兰的明明是柯南和阿笠博士
Anyway, she's okay now. That's the most important.
总之没事就好了
Is this true?
这是真的吗
Yes!
是的
Guys! Officer Sato has been awake!
各位 佐藤警官已经清醒了
No need to worry anymore!
不用担心了
Really?
是吗
Officer Sato!
佐藤警官
That's great, Takagi-san!
太好了 高木老哥
Great!
太好了
Finally, it ended well.
总算圆满结束了
What are you talking about?
这是什么话
There's still a Toshiya's extortion case pending.
现在还有一件敏也的恐吓案
Although the victim is dead,
被害人虽然已经死了
we still have to deal with this case seriously.
但仍须查明事实严肃处理
Yes, sir!
明白
It seems that you are still the one...
看来先让真相大白的…
who let the truth come out first.
似乎还是你
What are you?
你到底是
Need not to know.
Need not to know 「无须知道」
I'm just an ordinary pupil.
我只是个平凡的小学生
Thank you, Conan-kun.
谢谢你 柯南
The reason you said those words at that time
当时你是为了让我恢复记忆
is to stimulate me to recover my memory, right?
才那么说的吧
When we in the restaurant, you must have heard
你一定是在饭店里听到
what my father said to my mother when he proposed to her, right?
我爸对我妈求婚时说的话吧
I love you.
我爱你
More than anyone else on this planet.
比这地球上的任何一个人都要爱
So you intentionally said the same thing to me.
所以你才故意说同样的话
Uncle Mouri said it too?
叔叔也…
Didn't you?
不是吗
Yeah... You're right.
不 没…没错
See, I knew it.
看吧 我就知道
After all, there's an huge age difference between us.
我们的年纪毕竟差太多了
But I'm really happy. Good night.
不过我好高兴 晚安
Good night.
晚安
Fine.
算了
Wait, does that mean...
慢着 这么说
I'm thinking in the same way as Uncle Mouri?
我和叔叔岂不是同一思考模式
No way.
真是的